Sina Sajadmanesh Last update: 21 May, 2021

CONTACT INFORMATION Rue Marconi 19 1920 Martigny Switzerland (+41) 27-721-77-58 **\**sajadmanesh@idiap.ch 

https://sajadmanesh.com 

♣

RESEARCH SUMMARY My research interests lie at the intersection of privacy, deep learning, and graph analysis. More specifically, I use privacy enhancing technologies, such as differential privacy and federated learning, with graph representation learning algorithms, including graph neural networks, to make them more private, secure, and robust for real-world applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, May 2019 – May 2023

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering GPA: 5.75 / 6

**Thesis:** Learning over Graphs: A Privacy-Preserving Approach

Adviser: Prof. Daniel Gatica-Perez

**Relevant Courses:** Artificial Neural Networks (Deep Reinforcement Learning), Deep Learning for Natural Language Processing, Advanced Topics in Machine Learning

Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran, Sep 2014 – Sep 2016

M.Sc. in Information Technology Engineering GPA: 18.1 / 20

Thesis: Link Prediction in Heterogeneous Multi-Layer Social Networks

Adviser: Prof. Hamid R. Rabiee

**Relevant Courses:** Machine Learning, Complex Dynamical Networks, Performance Modeling of Computer Systems, Advanced Network Security, Database Security and Privacy

University of Isfahan, Esfahan, Iran, Sep 2009 – Feb 2014

B.Sc. in Computer Software Engineering GPA: 16.19 / 20 (Last four semesters: 17.4 / 20)

Project: Design and Implementation of an Android App for Voice Control of Household Devices

Adviser: Prof. Ahamd R. Naghsh-Nilchi

**Relevant Courses:** Data Structures, Algorithms, Probability and Statistics, Artificial Intelligence, Information Retrieval, Software Engineering, Databases, Operating Systems, Computer Networks

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Research Assistant, May 2019 – present

Social Computing Group, Idiap Research Institute, Martigny, Switzerland

• Developing privacy-preserving graph neural network models using differential privacy to reduce the privacy risks of using graph representation learning algorithms in real applications.

**Research Assistant**, (Offered, but declined due to visa problems)

IBM-ILLINOIS Center for Cognitive Computing Systems Research, **University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign**, Champaign, Illinois, United States

#### Research Assistant, Nov 2014 - May 2019

Data Science and Machine Learning Lab, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

- Privacy-Preserving Deep Learning: Worked on a hybrid approach based on Siamese fine-tuning and split learning to make non-private pre-trained deep learning models privacy-preserving at the inference stage.
- Web Data Science: Analyzed a large-scale collection of recipes published on the web and their content, aiming to understand cuisines and culinary habits around the world.
- <u>Social and Information Networks:</u> Developed time-aware link prediction algorithms over heterogeneous social networks using recurrent neural networks and non-parametric machine learning.

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

#### Guest Lecturer, Fall 2017

Department of Computer Engineering, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

**Course:** Fundamentals of Programming (Python) **Website:** http://ce.sharif.edu/courses/96-97/1/ce153-12/

#### **Teaching Assistant**

#### **EPFL**

• Computational Social Media (Head TA), Spring 2021

#### **Sharif University of Technology**

- Artificial Intelligence (Head TA), Spring 2017
- Advanced Topics in Artificial Intelligence Statistical Learning Theory, Spring 2016
- Engineering Probability and Statistics, Spring 2016

#### University of Isfahan

- Artificial Intelligence, Fall 2013
- Advanced Computer Programming 2 JavaFx and Android, Fall 2012

Sina Sajadmanesh Last update: 21 May, 2021

- Computer Programming Java, Fall 2011
- Computer Programming C++, Fall 2010

# INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

#### Big-Data Engineer, Sep 2018 – May 2019

Sharif ICT Innovation Center, Tehran, Iran

 Responsible for building a native big-data processing platform using state of the art technologies, such as Spark, Cassandra, JanusGraph, Elasticsearch, etc.

#### Software Engineering Intern, Summer 2012

Amin Computer Co., Esfahan, Iran

Responsible for designing and developing an Android application for company's web-based human resource management system.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### [1] Sina Sajadmanesh and Daniel Gatica-Perez

#### **Locally Private Graph Neural Networks**

ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2021), Nov 2021

[2] Seyed Ali Osia, Ali Shahin Shamsabadi, Sina Sajadmanesh, et al. A Hybrid Deep Learning Architecture for Privacy-Preserving Mobile Analytics IEEE Internet of Things Journal, May 2020

[3] Sina Sajadmanesh, Sogol Bazargani, Jiawei Zhang, and Hamid R. Rabiee Continuous-Time Relationship Prediction in Dynamic Heterogeneous Information Networks ACM Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data, Aug 2019

[4] Sina Sajadmanesh, Jiawei Zhang, and Hamid R. Rabiee NPGLM: A Non-Parametric Method for Temporal Link Prediction *Technical Report, ArXiv e-prints*, Jun 2017

[5] Sina Sajadmanesh, Sina Jafarzadeh, Seyed Ali Ossia, et al. Kissing Cuisines: Exploring Worldwide Culinary Habits on the Web International World Wide Web Conference (WWW 2017) Companion, Apr 2017

[6] Sina Sajadmanesh, Hamid R. Rabiee and Ali Khodadadi Predicting Anchor Links between Heterogeneous Social Networks IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining, Aug 2016

#### Media Coverage

- MIT Technology Review, How Data Mining Reveals the World's Healthiest Cuisines, 3 Nov 2016
- The Independent, These are the world's most diverse cuisines, 11 Nov 2016
- France 24, Un algorithme compare les cuisines du monde en matière d'ingrédients et d'apports nutritionnels,
   15 Nov 2016
- Sciences et Avenir, Les cuisines du monde passées au crible des big data, 14 Nov 2016

#### INVITED

### Locally Private Graph Neural Networks, Jan 2021

TALKS

Twitter Machine Learning Seminar

#### Privacy-Preserving Deep Learning Over Graphs, Dec 2020

Information Processing and Communications Lab, Imperial College London, UK

## PROFESSIONAL

• Reviewer: IEEE Transactions on Big Data (2021)

SERVICES

- Reviewer: Distributed and Private Machine Learning Workshop (2021)
- Reviewer: ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (2020)
- Reviewer: Social Network Analysis and Mining Journal (2020)
- Reviewer: World Wide Web Journal (2018)

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

- **PhD admission**, Computer Science, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2018 (declined)
- PhD admission Computer Science, Hong-Kong University of Science and Technology, 2017 (declined)
- Ranked 3rd in cumulative GPA among B.Sc. Computer Software Engineering students admitted for Fall 2009, University of Isfahan, 2014
- Ranked 6th in Iranian nationwide university entrance exam for graduate studies, field of Artificial Intelligence, among more than 100000 students, 2014
- Ranked 15th in Iranian nationwide university entrance exam for graduate studies, field of Computer Networks and Security, among more than 30000 students, 2014

Sina Sajadmanesh Last update: 21 May, 2021

 Ranked 28th in 18th National Computer Olympiad for University Students at Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran, 2013

- Ranked 16th in ACM-ICPC regional contest, Asia region, Tehran site, among more than 70 teams at University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran, 2011
- Ranked 2nd in nationwide collegiate programming contest among more than 70 teams at University of Kashan, Kashan, Iran, 2010
- Ranked among top 0.02% in Iran's nationwide university entrance exam for undergraduate studies., 2009

MEMBERSHIPS ACM Professional Member, 2020 – Present

ACM Student Member, 2011 - 2014

ACM-ICPC Student Chapter, University of Isfahan, Esfahan, Iran, 2010 – 2012

TECHNICAL Programming:

SKILLS Python, Java, C, C++, MATLAB, PHP, Javascript

Information Retrieval & Analytics: Elasticsearch, JanusGraph, Cassandra Data Science and Machine Learning:

PyTorch, PyTorch-Geometric, PyTorch-Lightning, Scikit-Learn, Pandas

REFERENCES Prof. Daniel Gatica-Perez, Idiap Research Institute, EPFL

Website: https://idiap.ch/~gatica Email: daniel.gatica-perez@epfl.ch

**Prof. Hamid R. Rabiee**, Department of Computer Engineering, Sharif University of Technology

**Prof. Hamed Haddadi**, Dyson School of Design Engineering, Imperial College London Website: https://haddadi.github.io/ Email: h.haddadi@imperial.ac.uk

Prof. Emiliano De Cristofaro, Department of Computer Science, University College London

Website: https://emilianodc.com/ Email: e.decristofaro@ucl.ac.uk